All right, so first we load up the webpage that was linked
in the instructor notes.
We see that it's populated already with some code for
the Happy Birthday TextView.
And then on the right, we see the preview and the device.
To change the text that appears here,
we need to change the value of the attribute called Android:text.
So in between the quotes here we can change the message.
Can change it to, hm, Happy Birthday to my pet hamster!
Then on the device, we can see that the text has now been updated, woohoo!
To change the size of the view, we can modify the width and
height attribute values.
The in between quotations, we can delete that and
change it to something like 250dp.
And then for the height we can change it to like 450dp.
And now, we see that the text view with the gray background is now a lot bigger.
Cool.
So, the last part of the quiz was to try to create an error.
So, if I delete the forward slash and the angle bracket, then,
I get a bunch of errors that show up on the bottom, here.
Also, the device greys out,
because there's no valid preview to show on the device anymore.
These errors can help you fix your code, and since we know what
we need to do to fix it, we can just hit Ctrl+Z to undo the changes we made.
The undo shortcut is really useful to use, so it's Cmd+Z on a Mac,
or Ctrl+Z on a Windows.
We can create other errors as well, such as deleting a quotation mark and
we see the error down here.
We can hit undo to make it come back.
Or we can change darker grey to parker grey,
which apparently Android doesn't recognize, unfortunately.
So we can just switch it back.