In a previous video, I showed you what happens when you set match parent for
the width of each of these child views.
The text view ends up extending across the full width of the parent.
There's no right or wrong solutions for how you experimented with the code.
Here's another thing you could've tried.
If you set the linear layout to have an orientation of horizontal,
then the views will be displayed in a horizontal row.
If you set match parent for the width of the VIP list,
then it unfortunately knocks off the other views off the screen.
If you set match parent for the height of the text you, then you see that
the VIP list text view is now the full height of the parent linear layout.
The same can be done for the other children views, or
you can set a fixed height.
In the previous video, we showed you what happens when you set matched parent
for the width of each of these child text views.
The text view extends to the full width of the parent linear layout.
If you set a fixed height on the TextView, like 300 DP,
then this is what it will look like on the device.
There's no right or wrong answers for what you tried out.